# MATTHEW GALVIN

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **OVERVIEW**

Proven technical lead with over eight years of experience in biotechnology and healthcare. I have a professional background in bioinformatics, data analysis, and software architecture with expertise in both product development and project management. My research interests include human health, equity, and philosophy.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Dana-Farber Cancer Institute**

#### Software Architect

Aug 2022 - Present

- · Engineering team lead for the MatchMiner project.
- $\cdot$  Python machine learning in support of  $\underline{\text{precision oncology efforts}}.$
- · ETL pipeline development and deployment.

Project Management, Airflow, Angular/React, Postgres, MongoDB

#### Invitae

#### **Bioinformatics Pipeline Engineer**

Jun 2021 - Jul 2022

- · Whole genome pipeline development.
- · Germline variant calling and data analysis.
- · Maintence and on-call support for reproductive health pipelines.

HPC, Python, Singularity, Shell Scripting

#### **Providence Health & Services**

#### **Bioinformatics Scientist**

Nov 2020 - Jun 2021

- $\cdot$  Whole exome & T/N pipeline development.
- · Bulk/scRNA data processing & machine learning.
- · Analysis and curation of AACR Project GENIE data.

AWS, Docker, Python, R, Shell Scripting, Nextflow, IGV

#### Genomics Software Engineer

May 2019 - Nov 2020

- · Oncogenic pipeline development and <u>data analysis</u>.
- · Full stack web development.
- · Application owner and engineering mentor.

GCP, Ruby/Rails, Javascript/React, Python, Postgres, MongoDB

#### Illumina, Inc.

#### Engineer, Life Cycle Management

Nov 2017 - Apr 2018

- · Manufacturing software automation.
- · Vendor quality control and cost management.
- · Establish software best practices with manufacturing partners.

Project Management, Manufacturing, Python, Shell Scripting, SAP

#### Software Test Engineer

Sep 2014 - Nov 2017

- · Lead software test engineer for mid-throughput sequencers.
- · Engineering management and product planning.
- · Instrumentation software verification and validation.

Product Management, Genomics, Test Driven Design, JIRA, JAMA

#### **EDUCATION**

B.S. Chemical Engineering Oregon State University, 2014

# **LANGUAGES**

Experienced in Python, R, Ruby, JavaScript, and Shell Scripting.

# **SKILLS**

- · Software Architecture
- · Genomics & Bioinformatics
- · Pipeline Development
- · Machine Learning
- · Docker & Singularity
- · High performance computing (HPC)
- · Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- · Google Cloud Platform (GCP)
- · Full-stack Web Development
- · API & UI & DB Design
- · Material-UI & Bootstrap & jQuery
- · React & Angular
- · Flask & Ruby on Rails & Express
- · Data Visualization
- · D3 & ggplot & matplotlib
- · MSSQL & Snowflake
- · Postgres & Mongo
- · Process Automation
- · Software Verification & Validation
- · JIRA & JAMA & SAP
- · Agile & Scrum
- · Github & Bitbucket & GitLab
- · Project & Product Management
- · MacOS & Linux & Windows
- · Adobe Creative Suite
- · CITI Certification
- · LATEX

#### LINKS

- · matthewrgalvin.com
- · linkedin.com/in/matthewrgalvin
- · github.com/galvinma
- · orcid.org/0000-0003-2040-8567